## Bas Machielsen

Phone: (+31) 6 23 78 66 29 Email: a.h.machielsen@uu.nl URL: http://bas-m.netlify.app

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/bas-machielsen-bobao4127

Github: https://github.com/basm92

Born: September 30, 1992 Nationality: Dutch

#### Current positions

PhD Student, Utrecht University, Netherlands

I am a PhD student in economic and financial history. My research analyzes political elites, the interaction between economic interests and politics, connections between politicians and firms, and politicians' investment behavior. My research is conducted within the framework of the NWO-project Investment behaviour, political change and economic growth in the Netherlands, 1780-1920.

Supervisors: prof. dr. O. C. Gelderblom, prof. dr. A. de Jong

#### Areas of specialization

Political economy, economic history, institutional economics, empirical finance

### Previous appointments

2020	Thesis supervisor, Rotterdam School of Management, Erasmus University, Netherlands
2016-2017	Researcher, University of Twente, Enschede, Netherlands
2014-2015	Teaching Assistant to prof. dr. R.M. Kabir for Corporate Finance, Corporate Governance, Fi-
	nancial Accounting, University of Twente, Enschede, Netherlands

#### Education

2015-2016	MSc in Economics (78 EC), cum laude, Radboud University Nijmegen
2014-2015	MSc in Business Administration (65 EC), University of Twente
2014	Pre-MSc in Economics (60 EC), Radboud University Nijmegen
2010-2013	BSc in Business Administration (180 EC), University of Twente

## Other Education

2020 2016-2019 2019 2018 2017	Probability: The Science of Uncertainty and Data, MIT Various completed courses on MOOC platforms, including Logic for Economists, Causal Inference, Bayesian Statistics, Linear Algebra, and 14 others. Posthumus Institute, Basic Training as part of PhD-programme Research Design Course, European University Institute, Florence, Italy Applied Econometrics, Erasmus University Rotterdam
	Presentations
2020	"The Political Elite and the Welfare State", Graduate Seminar, Utrecht University, Utrecht, Netherlands
2019	"The wealth of the political elite in the Netherlands, 1877-1927", Financial History Seminar, Utrecht, Netherlands
2018	"The influence of electoral constraints on the composition of politicians", Research Design Course for PhD students, Florence, Italy
2018	N.W. Posthumus Institute, PhD Seminar 2, Antwerp, Belgium
2017	N.W. Posthumus Institute, PhD Seminar I, Brussels, Belgium
2016	"The drivers of profitability of Dutch Hospitals", University of Twente, Netherlands
	Teaching
2020	BSc and MSc Theses Supervision, Rotterdam School of Management, Erasmus University
	Supervision of 10 groups of BSc students and 10 MSc students in the areas of political connections, human capital, financial history and corporate governance. Student evaluation: 9/10
2018-2020	Big Data, Big Questions, undergraduate level, Utrecht University
	An undergraduate course about methodology and an introduction to data analysis.
2017-2019	Finance Bootcamp, Summer school Curious U, University of Twente, Netherlands
	A summer school on the basic principles of corporate finance and business valuation.
2014-2015	Teaching Assistant, Corporate Governance and Corporate Finance, University of Twente, Netherlands

# Programming Languages & Skills

R, Python, Stata, LaTEX, (R)Markdown, git, SQL, SAS, QGIS, Eviews, SPSS, HTML, CSS

## Languages

lands

Dutch (native), English (full working proficiency), French (full working proficiency), Russian (full working proficiency), German (limited working proficiency), Turkish (elementary)

# Miscellaneous & other activities

Creator, maintainer of several R packages, Member of PhD Council, PhD Representative N.W. Posthumus Institute, in possession of a driving licence.

Last updated: July 8, 2020